VISHNU VISWANATH

Mobile: +1 309 5502311

Email: vviswanath@mail.bradley.edu

Address: 1609 W Ayres Ave, Peoria, IL 61606

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishnuviswanath25
StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/864624/sonic

About Me

I am a tech-enthusiast with over four years of work experience. I am passionate about Big Data, Machine learning and eager to explore technologies in vogue.

Skills

Programming Languages	Java, Python,C#
BigData	MapReduce, Hive, Pig, Oozie, Storm, Kafka Flume , SOLR, R
Machine Learning	Mahout,Scipy, Numpy, Octave, Weka
NoSQL	MongoDB,Hbase
DBMS	Oracle 11g, MySQL, SQL Server 2008
Web	J2EE,JSP,SOAP,Web Services, IBM MQ,IBM MB, IBM WPS,
	Java Script, CSS, JQuery
Frameworks	Struts, Spring, Hibernate, Dozer
Application Servers	Apache Tomcat, WAS 6.1

Courses/Certifications

Machine Learning (100%)	Andrew-Ng (Coursera)	Dec-2014
M101P: MongoDB for Developers (90%)	MongoDB	Nov-2013
Data Mining with Weka (100%)	University of Waikato	Oct-2013
Introduction to Data Science (95.8%)	Bill Howe, University of Washington (Coursera)	Jun-2013
Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part 1 (71.1%)	Tim Roughgarden, Stanford University(Coursera)	Mar-2013
IBM, Proof Of Technology training on Message Broker	IBM	Oct-2011
Training on SOA architecture	TCS	2011
Training on Webservices	TCS	2011
Web Designing	NIIT	2004

Education

MS in CS	Bradley University 2015-16	
B.Tech in CS	Cochin University Of Science and Technology(CUSAT) 2006-10	68.15%
H.S.C	Kerala State Board Of Secondary Education - 2006	92.40%
SSLC	Kerala State Education Board -2004	92.50%

Work Experience – 4 years 5 months

Sr. Developer - BigData

AIG Data Services Private Limited November 2014 – July 2015



IT Analyst - I

Caterpillar India Pvt. Ltd. October 2012 – October 2014



Assistant Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services February 2011 – September 2012



Projects

Organization: AIG Data Services Private Ltd

Project Name: Security Data Analytics

Security Data Analytics is used for analysis syslog files from different data sources. Flume tcp-agent listens to the port where the data is streamed, and stores it into HDFS. Once the data is stored into HDFS, a Pig script parses data using custom PigLoader and indexes the parsed data into SOLR. A parser is created for each data source and the PigLoader follows chain-of-responsibility design pattern to identify the message source and pass the message to the correct Parser. This script runs every 15 minutes and is scheduled using Oozie coordinator. A webservice is created which provides API to fetch data from SOLR, which is used by the Thin client. Thin client provides intrusion detection, network failure prediction and also Ad-hoc search capability. SOLR is integrated with Mahout for classification.

Role: Developer, Teamlead

Solution Environment: Flume, Oozie, PIG, SOLR, J2EE, Webservice, Mahout

Organization: Caterpillar India Pvt. Ltd.

Project Name: Unison

Caterpillar global Unison Project is a project under Caterpillar Finance. In this project I was involved in the design and development of Unison internal websites. The pages where designed in asp.net and used MSSQL as the database.

Role: Developer

Solution Environment: C#,Asp.net, CSS, Jquery,HTML 5, MSSQL

Project Name: MineStar

MineStar is a product for controlling and monitoring entire operations in a mine site. It has different modules like, Command - which can control vehicles remotely, Assign- which can assign tasks, Production estimation, Load mine model etc. It also provides the ability to manage Truck shifts and monitoring the Health of each truck in the mine field

Role: Developer

Solution Environment: Java, Spring, Hibernate, Oracle11g, SQL server

Organization: TCS

Project Name: SAUA

SAUA is a Loyalty application built on SOA. It deals the business of STAR Alliance group Member airlines. It handles message processing between airline system in different format and for loyalty based upgrade of ticket using miles. New airlines integrate with existing system by means of Web Services.

Role: Developer

Solution Environment: J2EE, Struts, Web Services, WID, Oracle, IBM MQ, WAS, IBM MB,

SUSE Linux.

Academic Projects:

Project Name: Blind Browser

A web based application for the Visually Challenged people using text-to-speech and speech-to-text. User's voice input is converted into text using Spinx speech to text converter. The content from the web page is parsed and is converted in to speech using java Speech API.

Solution Environment: Java, Windows

Project Name: Mobile PC Controller

The software for controlling the personal systems remotely using SMS feature of mobile. Which feature SMS based system controller that will enable to pass any command line argument to the

remote system and there by carrying out tasks. It provides users to add new commands along with inbuilt set of tasks available.

Solution Environment: C Sharp.Net, Windows Mobile

Accomplishments

- Reviewer of book Learning Apache Mahout Classification(ISBN13-9781783554959)
- Received the top performer award during TCS training.
- First in Kerala State -A Chess Championship, , Calicut, 1995
- First in Kerala State -B Chess Championship, 1995
- 34th in VII National Chess Festival 1994, AICF, Calicut, 1994
- 20th in the 10th National Boys Chess Championship, Bombay Chess Association, Bombay, 1996